import 'question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question:
        '1. Where is Bangladesh located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Europe',
      'b) Ocenia',
      'c) North America',
      'd) Asia'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '2. What is the most earned movie in 2023',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Barbie',
      'b) Oppenheimer',
      'c) Super Mario Bros',
      'd) Spiderman into the spiderverse'
    ],
  ),
   Question(
     question:
        '3. In which year did Bangladesh win their first-ever ICC tournament, the ICC Trophy (now ICC Cricket World Cup Qualifier)?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 2,
     options: ['a) 1995', 'b) 2000', 'c) 1997', 'd) 2003'],
   ),
   Question(
     question:
         '4. Who is the only Bangladeshi bowler to take a Test match hat-trick?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 1,
     options: [
       'a) Mashrafe Mortaza',
       'b) Taijul Islam',
       'c) Rubel Hossain',
       'd) Shakib Al Hasan'
     ],
   ),
   Question(
     question:
         '5. Which is the longest river in the world?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 2,
     options: [
       'a) Great Ganga',
       'b) Nile',
       'c) Amazon',
       'd) Padma'
     ],
   ),
   Question(
     question:
         '6.What term is used to describe a forest ecosystem characterized by trees that lose their leaves seasonally',
     correctAnswerIndex: 1,
     options: [
       'a) mangrove forest',
       'b) Deciduous forest',
       'c) Tropical rainforest',
       'd) Taiga forest'
     ],
   ),
  
   Question(
     question:
         '7. Who won ballon dor this year?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 1,
     options: [
       'a) Neymar',
       'b) Lionel MESSI',
       'c) C.Ronaldo',
       'd) Harry Maguire'
     ],
   ),

   Question(
     question:
         '8. Which is the largest ocean in the world?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 1,
     options: [
       'a) Indian',
       'b) Pacific',
       'c) Arctic',
       'd) Atlantic'
     ],
   ),

   Question(
     question:
         '9. Tsunami is a word in which language?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 2,
     options: [
       'a) Russian',
       'b) Urdu',
       'c) Japanese',
       'd) Malay'
     ],
   ),

   Question(
     question:
         '10. Which is the smallest country in the world?',
     correctAnswerIndex: 0,
     options: [
       'a) Vatican City',
       'b) Bhutan',
       'c) Nepal',
       'd) Sri Lanka'
     ],
   ),

  
];